JACOB KOLB

1145 East 2570 North • Provo, Utah 84604 • (801) 636-6179 • ikolb12@gmail.com

CAREER PROFILE

I have 13 years' experience in electronic design, development, and manufacturing. I've worked in industries ranging from outdoor adventure and action sport to military, security and defense. Most operations I join are small startup organizations. I have experienced the growth challenges as these teams become mature organizations and businesses. I specialize in technical communication, team work, leadership, engineering, NPI, test, automation, and planning.

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

- International CES Innovations Design and Engineering Award Goal Zero
- Stock market launch, IPO Skullcandy
- Partnership with Toshiba Fortem Technologies
- Company acquisition by a multibillion industry leader Goal Zero

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Fortem Tech. Pleasant Grove, Utah August 2017 to January 2022



Fortem Technologies is a leader in airspace awareness and counter small Unmanned Aerial System (UAS) that uses an end to end system of networked radar systems, AI, sensor integration. Fortem designs and manufactures its proprietary technology in the USA. ITAR approved and AS9100D compliant.

Production Engineering Manager/Project Manager (June 2021 to January 2022)

Work with hardware, software, and business development teams to derive production requirements and manufacturing solutions, as a system, for operations to execute and deliver hundreds of systems a year. Supporting +9 different devices of varying complexity with +30 system configuration. Direct report of +10 individuals.

- Lead teams of engineers and technicians to support company portfolio objectives
- Coordinate with development and operations managers to assess priority
- Develop and refine engineering requirements to align with stakeholders, business needs, schedule, and cost
- Plan short and long term goals to satisfy engineering requirements
- New Product Introduction planning and coordination
- Develop project proposals and write project financial reports
- Create and execute ECRs and ECOs on released hardware and software
- GitLab repo management and merge request approvals
- Continuous deployment of hardware, software and documentation as a manufacturing system
- Generate, prepare, aggregate, and maintain device history

TrueView Technician Manager/Production Manager (August 2019 to June 2021)

Manage end to end production and manufacturing two radar systems, +16 configurations including custom customer specifications needed to meet international standards. Support manufacturing solutions for in-house and contract manufacturing.

- Manage daily tasks and goals of technician team to achieve long term goals and plans
- Give trainings on lab safety including OSHA and MSDS (SDS)
- Give trainings on lab skills: SMT Soldering, PCBA troubleshooting, measurement, ESD, RF equipment, and calibrations
- Manage schedules for large orders to ensure on time delivery
- Develop, release, and support radar calibration software utilities
- Organize Kanban and Sprints to achieve goals

Algorithm Engineer / Jr. Radar Systems (January 2019 to June 2021)

Develop autonomous robotic systems to calibrate radars. Integrating a variety of equipment such as: power supplies, vector network analyzers, spectrum analyzers, signal generators, switches, variable amps and attenuators, stepper motors and much more. Write scripts to collect and process radar data. Primary languages: Python, C/C++, and SQL.

- Data visualization: plots, charts, histograms, distributions, ect...
- Develop manual processes, as much as possible, to ensure good processes are discovered then automate those processes
- Develop radar calibration techniques
- Develop radar calibration algorithms and routines
- Advanced indexing to process multiple dimensional data
- Process radar data and search desired target or characteristic
- Extract, transform, load data into database; database queries and analysis
- Automate and integrate RF and robotics equipment to perform 3D calibrations
- Performance optimization as needed for production requirements



Goal Zero Bluffdale, Utah

July 2012 to September 2015

Goal Zero is a leader in portable power, providing solar and battery power solutions from small cell phones up to large household appliances. In addition to providing solutions to the consumer market, Goal Zero is heavily involved in humanitarian efforts to provide reliable power to developing areas around the world.

Business Development Technical Lead (2012 to 2015)

- Product Manager Goal Zero Street Charge
- Quality Assurance Assistant Manager
- Cultivate relations with suppliers and manufacturers to improve workflow and lead times
- Visit with customers on site during first deployment to ensure good communication and create lasting relationships.

Solution Center Lead Technical Representative (2012)

- Edit highly technical user manuals to increase customer understanding
- Provide timely and accurate solutions for computationally intensive customer inquiries and problems for both commercial and consumer applications
- Administrator of Goal Zero social media



Skullcandy Park City, Utah

November 2010 to July 2012



Skullcandy produces audio speakers as headphones, earphones, hands free devices, and apparel while maintaining a large presence in the action sport arena and general consumer market.

Customer Service Representative (2010 to 2012)

- Manage Ebay order fulfillments
- Resolve up to 150 customer inquiries daily by phone or email
- Guide customers to best fitting products for up sale
- Build rapport, listen, and clarify customer situation to provide outstanding solutions

EDUCATION

WESTERN GOVERNORS UNIVERSITY, SLC, Utah, Graduation: Summer 2022

B.S. Computer Science – Emphasis in Automation and Algorithms

UTAH VALLEY UNIVERSITY, Orem, Utah, Graduation 2015

A.S. Applied Sciences – Emphasis in Biology and Chemistry

EXTRACURRICULAR & VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES

Boy Scouts of America, Provo, Utah, 2006

• Eagle Scout and Bronze Eagle Palm

Latter Day Saint Church, Piura, Peru, 2008 to 2010

- Zone leader of +20 subordinates, 20% increase in conversion rate over 3 months
- Financial Secretary managing over 250 accounts and cash flow of 10,000 Soles
- Senior partner, trainer, and district leader